

- sandeepkhoj@gmail.com
- Jaipur, Rajasthan, India
- +91 9261231405
- github.com/xenotime-india
- linkedin.com/in/xenotime

Skills



JavaScript ES6, TypeScript, React, Next.js, Semantic HTML, CSS, Web Accessibility (A11y, WCAG, ARIA), Vercel, Serverless, MongoDB, Node.js, Git, Live Audio, Audio and Video Production, Ableton Live, Public Speaking



Angular, Webpack, Java, Adobe CC (Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere), Developer & Project Management



Vue.js, Python, AWS, Dev Ops, DigitalOcean, Redis, Websockets, C++, JUCE

Sandeep Kumar

Platform Architect | Full Stack Developer | Programming Geek

I am a full stack developer with an emphasis on the front end. I specialize in building large-scale, performant, and user-friendly applications in React. Throughout my career, I have expressed a strong eye for design, and I take the user experience seriously!

Professional Experience

Platform Architect

Traction On Demand India Private Limited

- - <u>Traction REC</u> / <u>Traction On Demand</u> Traction Rec is the first full-service recreation management system powered by Salesforce.com, the world's #1 CRM software. The platform is designed to run the daily operations of community centers, including memberships, programs, facilities, fundraising and engagement. Built by Salesforce's most trusted partner, Traction on Demand, Traction Rec was developed to empower organizations by maximizing the impact they have in the communities they serve. undefinedundefined

Technical Architect | Principle Consultant

Appirio India Private Limited

- December 2013-June 2019
 - LillyNow portal / Lilly (currently working) Lilly has over 80 disparate portals that serve multiple affiliates, markets and departments across 40,000 employees in 120 countries. They required one common experience for all employees that will combine the features and content from those disparate portals into one easy to use, mobile-optimized, personalized and dynamic solution. We rebuild their intranet portal for their employees. The vision of this project is to provide a common platform to all the employees wherein they can communicate and collaborate with one another. My job is to write Contentful, Kaltura rest API in Node.js implement front on react.js.
 - LUCID / Lilly Built various private node modules related to security, PDF Doc generation from Markdown files, encapsulate this SSO authentication implementation. These modules will be used internally for reducing this effort in future projects.
 - Lids / Lids Built an android and iOS mobile app on React-Native where enduser can shop the ultimate destination for the latest styles in hats, fan gear, and occasionally licensed sports apparel. Also can join Lids new Access Pass loyalty program and earn points each time you shop. Plus, get access to exclusive offers! We have also built various microservices on Heroku to connect their legacy system which is required to make this mobile application.

- Align / <u>Align Technology</u> Bidirectional Integration office 365 calendar with Salesforce event. Written and exposed various REST service on salesforce which is used in there sales rep mobile application.
- BMC MyEBC iOS mobile app / BMC Worked alone for the BMC MyEBC app.
 The iOS app used for BMC executives and customers to schedule sales demos and meetings. Used the community as an extended team, as an when needed.
 Acted as a single point of contact, for the client, for everything associated with the app. Worked on all aspects of app, including but not limited to design, develop, testing and deployment.
- Mesho1 / Mesho1 Developed product testing postal on Node.js, AngularJs, MongoDb. Integrated IBM watson tone analyzer services to generate graphical chart report to show testing feedback.
- NCApp / <u>Nightingale Conant</u> Worked as a developer and build hybride mobile app for both iOS and android platform. We created an app for motivational training purpose. Using that app user can buy the subscription, watch videos and read/purchase books. We used Angular JS and Cordova(phonegap) framework in this app and video playback feature using Kaltura.
- SiBM Travel Companion / IBM Worked as a development resource and consultant for clients. Created rich, highly interactive responsive websites and UI components with JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3. Developed single-page angularJS application using Google Maps API v3 for major US retail brand.
- Tholos / <u>Kimberly Clark</u> Developed a mobile-optimised web app from the ground level. This involved: project planning, wireframing, database coding, writing .Net services, as well as HTML and CSS programming for the interface.

Senior Software Engineer

Metacube Private Limited

- May 2012-December 2013
 - Aegerion Pharmaceuticals Patient Portal on Salesforce over responsive UI to support mobile and desktop devices. Patient can login to portal as external user to track their LDL-C level and can know about the dieting plan to be followed to increase or decrease LDL-C level.
 - Experian Service cloud / Experian Herein we implemented service cloud services with the help of standard case object which include web to case, email to case, case assignment rules, Escalation rules, Knowledge one.
 - Teva Pharmaceutical Industries is an international pharmaceutical company headquartered in Petah Tikva, Israel. The project is mainly about to build Social Intranet. Using this Social Intranet (Edgeforce) their internal employees can collaborate and access their documents easily from their various devices like mobile, ipad and desktops.
 - B:C Service Cloud / Logitech Worked as a developer and build a case management system. We created a support site that is accessible from iPad, desktop and iPhone also. We set up a Customer Community for customers from where they can create and check status of their cases.

Software Engineer

Xtreme Infosoft Private Limited

- **Tebruary 2010–May 2012**
 - Sales Rep Application (ASP.Net, SQL Server, Jquery, HTML, CSS)/ <u>Delta Electronics India</u> Worked at the client-side location, Gurgaon wherein I

developed a web application for their sales team. With the help of the application, the sales representative used to give a clear understanding of their product. This app also gives them a platform to customize their product according to the client need. Once the final outlook of the product gets finalized by the customer its get shared with the production team for the final working on the order.

• Automation System (ASP.Net, SQL Server, Jquery, HTML, CSS) - This is a webbased application that has Entire updated information from the college/ institution will be made available to the Management, Employee, and Students accordingly. Has inbuilt database backup facility for safety and reliability. Single database management system. Performance analysis of the students or staff. It regulates the fee management process completely. Complete automation of sta administration.



Education

B.S. in Computer Science

1 Belmont University

My coursework included Java programming, Programming Languages, Data and File Structures, Operating Systems, Computer Organization, Discrete Mathematics, Combinatorics, Graph Theory, Artificial Intelligence, and others. As part of the Honors program, I also completed a final thesis titled Applications of Audio Analysis Algorithms Using Discrete Fourier Transforms.

B.S. in Audio Engineering Technology

1 Belmont University

I worked with professional engineers and producers in the recording industry, and trained in several world-class recording studios such as the Historic RCA Studio B and Ocean Way Nashville.



Hobbies & Interests

Most of my free time is spent creating music! I enjoy many elements of performance and production, and I play the guitar, piano, and drums. My professional training in audio engineering and my access to a well-equipped home studio leads to top quality audio and video production for music, podcasting, live streaming on Twitch, demo videos, and even Zoom video calls.

Additionally, I enjoy tabletop gaming, video games, travel, and podcasting. My wife and I host an anime podcast called The AniMonday Podcast.

On the side, I designed, created, and continue to maintain the following websites: dotdotdarknessmusic.com, animonday.moe